

TROY ATKINSON

C# PROGRAMMER (UNITY)

INFO

troymakes.games

troymakesgames@gmail.com

in <u>in/TroyMakesGames</u>

TroyMakesGames

@TroyMakesGames

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Multiplayer Coding
- Prototyping
- Leadership
- Architecture Design
- Agile Development
- CICD
- Unit Testing
- Code Reviewing
- Public Speaking

SOFTWARE

- Unity
- C#
- NodeJs
- Swift
- Kotlin
- Java
- C++
- C

EDUCATION

2019

Master of Arts: Entrepreneurship

Falmouth University

2018

Bachelor of Arts: Game

PROFILE

Unity programmer specializing in gameplay, architecture and multiplayer. I pride myself in my ability to drive features from concept to completion, with a focus on code quality, performance and scalability.

I love working in teams, and spend most of my time learning from, mentoring or collaborating with my co-workers. I work best in an agile, feedback-driven environment.

I've spent years making games, tools for games and game-related software. I have a deep understanding of Unity and C# and I've got a fast-paced, adaptable approach to learning.

KEY SKILLS

Gameplay Programming

- Built special enemy types, powerups, repairs and other gameplay systems for the FPS shooter Stuffed
- Created an isometric combat system and its unique input systems for Inkbound (Mirror Networking)
- Built arcadey co-op ship-to-ship combat, powerups, and a wealth of other gameplay features for RoBoats (Forge Networking Remastered)
- Built gameplay features for a multiplayer survival-horror game, including pickups, player-to-player interactions and combat (Forge Networking)

Unity Development

- <u>Unity Certified Developer</u> with a deep understanding of the engine
- Built editor extensions to support the design and testing of game features, including node graphs, settings menus and network code generation tools
- Designed and built a CI/CD workflow which incorporates GitHub Actions, C# and Bash to creates managed libraries, repairs asset references and deploy a Unity package
- Comfortable with Unity's new Input System, Addressables and the new render pipelines
- Manage comms between Unity and Audiomob, including reporting issues and working with Unity's engineers to find workarounds

Development (Programming) **Falmouth University**

2015

BTEC: Games Development City College Plymouth

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Unity Certified Developer

Credential ID: 201708UCD2704

Supermassive Games Award

Supermassive Games – March 2018

VOLENTEERING

Head Conference Associate, Tandem Events

- Managed 20+ conference associates at multiple <u>Develop</u> <u>Brighton</u> events
- Organized schedules and keep the team on track
- Trained and supported conference associates
- Worked directly with the Director of the conference to ensure the smooth running of the events

SIDE PROJECTS

Homebound

- Mobile game app designed to help users manage their mental wellbeing in lockdown
- Built in a few days as part of a charity game jam
- Collaborated with a writer, artist and audio designer to build, test and polish the game in a short space of time
- Available on <u>iOS</u>, <u>Android</u> and <u>web</u>

Cornwall: My Home

- Designed and built a <u>parody</u> <u>farming simulator game</u> based on my home county of Cornwall for the Global Game Jam
- Coded tile and item

Adaptability

- Motivated by learning, I love the challenge of understanding new systems, environments and workflows
- Up-skilled in Swift to integrate an OS-level framework into a Unity project
- Self-taught NodeJS on-the-job to build and maintain <u>backend</u> <u>systems</u> that supported thousands of concurrent players
- Developed, start to finish, an Android plugin in Java to bridge device-level functionality with the Unity runtime
- Perform code reviews for and mentor team members working in C#,
 Swift, Kotlin and TypeScript

WORK HISTORY

August 2022 - Current

Staff Engineer, AudioMob

- Ensure the engineering team meets its functional and non-functional requirements
- Developed the Unity SDK's architect and monitor it's complexity
- Lead the building of features and fixes across the full stack
- Oversee technical planning of new features
- Manage technical support comms for clients
- Interview candidates and assess technical competence
- Ensure the engineering teams stays within it's error budgets
- Acts as a liaison between engineering teams to ensure a shared vision for multi-team projects
- Onboarded and trained engineering staff, including frequent mentoring
- Designed and implemented a CI/CD workflow for the SDKs

September 2020 – August 2022

Software Engineer, AudioMob

- Developed and maintained a Unity Plugin
- Proposed, prototyped and built a backend service
- Pitched our services to game development studios and publishers
- Managed client integrations
- Attended and represented the company at industry events
- Performed code reviews and tested other's work
- Wrote articles for AudioMob's website and external journalism sites
- Coordinated with companies to integrate their technology
- Expanded and improved the QA process
- Built and maintained demo games (iOS, Android)
- Coded in C#, JavaScript, ObjectiveC and Swift
- Used Google Cloud Services

- interactions, crop growth, weather and shop features in a short period of time
- Constantly tested throughout and added, removed and changed features based on feedback

Zurvive

- Currently designing and codeveloping an online survival game
- The game is still in early development but has player management, networked inventory system, player-toworld interactions and basic structure building
- Completely serverauthoritative

REFERENCES

See <u>LinkedIn</u> for recommendations, more references available upon request.

December 2017 - September 2020

Freelance Programmer

- Worked for a wealth of clients in and out of the games industry and often completed sequential contracts with the same companies
- Upskilled staff during my time with companies
- Built game features, plugins, AI systems and more
- Designed the technical architecture of Unity projects
- Clients included TruePlayers (game), Audimob (plugin), Waving Bear Studios (game), Falmouth University, Imperial College London, MetaMakers, Polyperfect (package) and more

September 2019 - February 2020

Backend Developer, Codices

- Developed and maintained backend services for Twitch extensions
- Expanded and maintained infrastructure and dev ops
- Designed, proposed and developed a game-mode for the product
- Represented the backend team in engineering meetings
- Introduced and trained staff in Agile methodologies
- Created <u>tutorial</u> and <u>promotional</u> video content
- Wrote guides for new users

January 2018 - September 2019

Co-Founded and Lead Developer, Animal Puree

- Co-founded the company as the Technical Lead
- Designed, proposed, prototyped and developed experimental technology that allowed players to use their mobile phones as gamepads (for Unity)
- Researched and presented the market viability of the technology
- Pitched successfully for funding and incubation
- Lead the development of two games to showcase and promote the technology
- Managed 6+ developers working on the games
- Tracked and reviewed the progress of members of the team
- Showcased the technology at industry events (including EGX)
- Directed and edited trailers for the demo games (<u>here</u> and <u>here</u>)

December 2017 - August 2018

Lead Unity Developer, Unsalted

- Hired as a developer but shortly moved to project lead
- Lead the development of a <u>hyper-casual mobile game</u>
- Hired and managed freelancers on the project
- Interviewed and onboarded members of the engineering team
- Represented the technical team in department meetings
- Created schedules and ensured the completion of milestones